Yanik Laube

Address: Sydney, Australia
Mobile: (+61) 450 911 599
Nationality: Australian and Swiss
E-mail: yanik.laube@gmail.com
http://yanik.laube.com/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yanik-laube/

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Currently working in a front-end development role in the Banking and Financial Services division at Macquarie Group. Previously was working on the algorithmic trading development team in the Commodities and Global Markets division. Interested in leveraging technological, mathematical, financial, and analytic skills to positively contribute to an organisations corporate and departmental objectives, while gaining valuable industry experience.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Associate - Macquarie Group, Sydney, Australia

2022 - Present (Full Time)

Digital Car Loans Online Team (Aug 2022 - Present):

- Developed and launched the new digital car loans service
- Front-end development work on the website using Angular, HTML, TypeScript, CSS
- Worked in an Agile environment with daily stand-ups, kept track of user stories in Jira & Bitbucket, and conducted weekly sprint planning and retrospectives every week

Algorithmic Trading Development Team (Feb 2022 - Aug 2022):

- · Continued work on the same team as during my internship on the algorithmic trading systems
- Worked on all parts of the development cycle from designing, coding, QA, deployment, and server maintenance

Internship - Macquarie Group, Sydney, Australia

2020 - 2021 (Full Time)

Algorithmic Trading Development Team (Dec 2020 - Feb 2021):

- Part of the algorithmic trading team in the Corporate Operations Group aligned with CGM cash equities
- Full stack development on a system named Helios which manages algorithmic trading orders, using C#, .Net, Microsoft Visual Studio, JetBrains Rider, Windows Forms, and WPF
- Implemented features requested by stakeholders in a real-time, event-driven, distributed application environment

Espressorium, Gold Coast, Australia

2014 - 2017 (Part Time)

Australian based retailer offering coffee capsules and accessories to businesses and consumers.

- Develop a program to calculate the most economical shipping method to use for each specific order
- Ongoing analysis, improvement and implementation of most efficient packing and shipping procedures

EDUCATION

The University of Queensland, Australia

2015 - 2021

Bachelor of Computer Science and Bachelor of Mathematics. Taking additional courses in financial mathematics as well. Completed classes on these related topics:

Financial Mathematics Analysis of Scientific Data Computer Graphics & Data Analysis

Software Engineering Advanced Database Systems Probability & Statistics
Algorithms & Data Structures Intro to Information Systems Intro to Computer Systems
Statistical Modelling & Analysis Numerical Methods in Comp Sci Programming in the Large

SKILLS

Programming: Java, Python, C, C#, CSS, HTML, TypeScript, Angular, React, SQL, WPF, WinForms, R

Database Systems: MySQL, Oracle, MS Access
Operating Systems: Windows, macOS, Linux

Software:Visual Studio IDE, Eclipse IDE, IntelliJ IDE, JetBrains Rider, Atmel Studio, MATLAB, MS OfficeFinancial:Portfolio Optimisation, Futures & Forward Contracts, DCF Valuation, Risk ManagementLanguages:English – Native, German – Fluent, Japanese and Spanish – Elementary Proficiency

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Text Search Application, Java

Aug 2018 - Oct 2018

Implemented a general textual search application using different algorithms and data structures to search through large text documents most efficiently.

Programs to Perform Mathematical Tasks, MATLAB, C

Aug 2017 - Oct 2017

Wrote various programs to do things such as polynomial approximation on large data sets, calculating derivatives, solving partial differential equations, Gaussian elimination, Monte Carlo integration, etc.

AVR Microcontroller Program, C

Mar 2017 - Jul 2017

Created a program for the AVR ATmega324A microcontroller to play my own modified version of Snake. It would receive inputs (from a serial port, buttons, etc.) and output information onto an LED matrix.

Event Scheduling GUI, Java

Feb 2017 - Jun 2017

Designed a program to best allocate events to venues depending on venue capacity, location, and traffic. Designed to be able to read and load in data about the events and venues and included a GUI for the user